贝克特
Beckett!
卡塞尔  我在这儿
Castle, I'm here!
贝克特  坚持住
Beckett, hang on!
要么是我在做一个无聊透顶的梦
Either this is the most boring dream I've ever had
要么是你也睡不着
or you can't sleep either.
不是做梦  噩梦还差不多
It's not a dream. More like a nightmare.
在烦毕业生代表演讲的事吗
Is this about your valedictorian speech?
我终于有机会说点重要的事
It's my chance to say something important,
有意义的事
something worthy.
我不想搞砸了
I don't want to blow it,
但我又觉得没什么可说的
But I feel like I have nothing to say.
你是在跟
You mean nothing compared to
人类的宗教经文
the great sacred texts of mankind
温斯顿·丘吉尔在哈罗公学的演讲
or Winston Churchill's speech to Harrows,
或者乔布斯在斯坦福的演讲相比吗
or Steve Jobs' address to stanford?
也许你应该找些平常一点的
You know, maybe you should pick some speeches
演讲来做参照
that is a little less daunting to compare yours to,
比如《情到深处》或者《暮光之城》
like, um, "Say anything" or "Twilight."
不应该这么难的啊
It's not supposed to be this hard.
生命中最有价值的东西
You know, the most worthwhile things in life
往往最难得到
are often the most difficult.
比如说
For example--
这手机真够智能的
Wow. That really is a smart phone.
你当然不明白
Of course you don't understand
为什么她这么重视毕业演讲
why she's taking her graduation speech so seriously.
你很可能是那种长袍底下
You were probably the guy who had nothing on but boxers
就穿了内裤的人
underneath his gown.
太瞧不起人了
That is so insulting.
不怕告诉你  我下面什么都不穿
If you must know, I was naked underneath.
不好意思  算我错了
Oh, I'm sorry. I stand corrected.
毕业生的爸爸有什么感想啊
So how is the father of the graduate taking it?
我已经计划好如何消愁了
I already have a plan to drown my sorrows.
典礼结束后  我妈去汉普顿
After the ceremony, my mother goes off to the Hamptons,
阿丽克西斯肯定是通宵有活动
Alexis will be doing her all-nighter.
我就连看《喋血双雄》和《毒手神探》
I will be distracting myself with a double feature
来转移下伤感情绪
of "The killer" and "Hard boiled."
这倒真算得上连看了
Wow. That is a double feature.
你也喜欢吴宇森吗
You like John Woo?
越血腥越好
The bloodier the better.
你想和我一块看吗
You wouldn't want to... join me, would you?
事实上  我很愿意
Actually, I'd love to.
走不走啊  卡塞尔
You coming, Castle?
这就来
Yeah. Please.
什么情况
So?
死者是西班牙裔男性  快30岁
So we've got a hispanic male, late 20s.
出租车司机大约一小时前发现尸体
Cabbie spotted the body about an hour ago
然后报警
and called it in.
知道他身份吗
We got an I.D.?
不知道  找过死者口袋
Nah. We checked his pockets.
没手机  没钥匙  没钱包
There's no phone, keys, or wallet.
现在正在检查指纹
And we're checking prints right now.
从血迹来看  应该是走进巷子之前
From the blood trail, it looks like he was shot
就中枪了
before he entered the alley.
他肩部的伤
He was hit in the shoulder
枪口径应为357
with what looks like a 357,
但致命枪是一支9毫米射出的
but the kill shot-- point-blank, execution style,
近距离处决式射击
with a 9 millimeter.
两把枪  可能凶手不止一个
Two guns. Could be more than one shooter.
鉴证组能追踪到第一枪留下
Was C.S.U. able to trace that blood trail
的血迹吗
from the first shot?
从转角处开始的
It starts around the corner.
现在还看不到源点
There's no visible point of origin,
不过鉴证组的人还在找
but the teams are still looking.
这附近可不怎么太平
Well, this is a bad neighborhood.
是不是抢劫出了岔子
Maybe it was a mugging gone wrong?
有可能
Maybe.
从他肩膀上的细槽看
These grooves in his shoulder indicate
他当时扛着很重的东西
that he was carrying something, and it was heavy.
至少14公斤
I'd say at least 30 pounds.
他手指甲里好像有些皮肤组织
I'm even seeing traces of skin tissue in his fingernail.
没准能验到DNA
I may be able to get D.N.A.,
等把他运回停尸间我就能进一步尸检了
But I'll know a lot more once I get him back to the morgue.
他口袋可能是空的
Uh, his pockets may have been empty,
不过他貌似在鞋里面藏了什么东西
but it looks like he was trying to hide something in his shoe.
锁镐
Lock picks?
什么人会随身带着锁镐呢
Now why would someone be needing lock picks?
他是个小偷
He's a thief.
奥兰多·科斯塔斯
Orlando Costas.
几次入室抢劫  涉嫌的抢劫案一堆
A couple of domestic B&Es, but suspected of a dozen more.
他曾是卡扎多斯帮的人
He used to run with the Cazadores.
卡扎多斯帮是什么
Cazadores?
一个贩卖毒品和武器  兼盗窃的街头帮派
They're a violent street gang that deals in drugs, arms, and larceny,
但他的前科都是少年时的事了
But all of Orlando's priors are back when he was a teenager.
他已经多年没犯过事了
He hasn't been arrested in years.
也许他又重出江湖了
Maybe he got back in the game.
不好说  他为改邪归正下了不少功夫
I don't know. He went a long way to clean up his act.
当了四年兵
Did four years active in the military,
去年光荣退伍
discharged with honors last year.
轮岗时去了德国做宪兵
Spent his rotation as an M.P. in Germany.
宪兵  他还真的改邪归正了
Military police? He really did clean up his act.
若这家伙已经改过自新了
If this guy went straight,
那怎么会死在小巷里
then how did he end up dead in an alley?
查过近亲了吗
Did you check for next of kin?
他家人都过世了
Uh, his folks are dead,
不过我们找到了他的女朋友玛丽萨尔·卡斯塔内塔
but we managed to track down a girlfriend-- Marisol Castaneda.
埃斯波西托现在正带她过来
Esposito's bringing her in right now.
我只知道  昨晚我上床睡觉的时候
All I know is, he was with me in bed last night
他还和我在一起的
when I went to sleep.
今早我醒来的时候
I woke up this morning,
他和我的车都不见了
and both him and my car were gone.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
我以为他去就业中心看工作招聘了
I figured he'd gone to the career center to check the job listings.
他每天早上都这样
He does that every morning.
他在找工作
He'd been looking for work?
都几个月了
For months.
奥兰多曾为国效力
Orlando served his country.
你以为这事总算有点分量
You'd think that means something,
可我们生活很困难
but it's been tough,
尤其是我的工时还减少了
especially after my hours got cut.
也就是说他有财务压力
So he was under financial pressure?
有没有可能他又重操旧业了
Is it possible that he went back to old habits?
不可能
No.
玛丽萨尔  我们知道他曾是卡扎多斯的一员
Look, Marisol, we know that he ran with the Cazadores.
-你觉得  -我说了不可能
- Do you think that-- - I said no.
他为脱离过去那种生活付出了许多
He went through hell to escape that life.
去参军  就是为了摆脱过去
It's why he enlisted, to get out,
为我重新做人
to be a better man for me...
为我们的儿子重新做人
a better father to our son.
请你们不要再把这事当成是他的错
So how about you stop trying to make this his fault
去找杀他的凶手吧
and find whoever killed him?
你的车是什么样的
What kind of car do you have?
离小巷两个街区
Two blocks away from the alley,
靠手上有血  肯定是这辆车
blood smeared on the arm rest-- this is definitely it.
他在别处遭到枪击然后跑这来了
He was shot somewhere else and then he came here?
为什么不回家  为什么不去处理伤口
Why not go home? Why not go get patched up?
他在那条小巷里和人会面
He was meeting someone in that alleyway.
有部电话
Phone.
最后一通电话是凌晨4点47  就在他死前
His last call was 4:47 a.m., just before he died.
-查一下那个号码  -好的
- Run that number. - Right.
贝克特  有支枪
Hey, Beckett, gun.
是38口径
It's a .38.
才开过火
Recently fired.
那就是枪战了
So it was a shootout.
他的肩伤是这么来的
That's how he got the shoulder wound.
那么不管他从哪逃过来  可能还有人死了
Which means, wherever he came from, there might be another body.
我知道他从哪逃过来
I know where he was coming from.
哪里
Where?
最后行车记录显示为第一大道299号
His last entry was 299 First Avenue.
等等  第一大道299号是哪里
Wait. What's at 299 First Ave.?
蒙哥马利警监家
Captain Montgomery's house.
真庆幸没人受伤
We're just thankful no one was hurt.
相信我  我也是
Believe me, so am I.
罗伊去世之后
Ever since Roy died,
我晚上睡觉都把他的357口径放在床头柜里
I've slept with his .357 in the nightstand.
只有一个人吗
So it was just the one guy?
据我所知是的
As far as I know.
他当时正从柜子里拿文件出来
He was taking files out of the cabinet.
背包里还装了罗伊的旧笔记本电脑
He had Roy's old laptop in his backpack.
他看到我的时候  就拿出了武器
When he saw me, he pulled his weapon,
上帝保佑  我冲他开了枪
so God help me, I shot him.
我好像击中了他的肩膀
I think I hit him in his shoulder.
他开枪还击了  然后跳窗逃了
He fired back, and then he crashed through the window.
伊芙琳  是这人吗
Evelyn, was this the guy?
没错  就是他
Yeah. That's him.
幸好孩子们都不在家
I'm glad Evan and the girls weren't home.
说来有趣
Funny thing is,
我也不应该在家的
I wasn't supposed to be home either.
好像他知道我们不会在家似的
It's almost like he knew we weren't supposed to be here.
那些文件有什么特别的吗
Anything special about those files?
就是些文案  法律文件
Just paperwork, legal documents,
罗伊旧案子的笔记
notes on Roy's old cases.
他的电脑呢  里面有什么
What about his computer? What-- what was on that?
他以前的工作文件
His old work files,
不过我现在大多用来放圣诞卡和食谱
but mostly, I use it for Christmas cards and recipes.
他们是去找蒙哥马利那些文件的
They went after Montgomery's files.
不要贵重物品  也不要现金
Not valuables, not cash.
现在那个小偷死了
And now our thief is dead
而他偷走的文件下落不明
and the files he took are missing?
别这么急着下论断
Well, let's not jump to conclusions.
闯进蒙哥马利家
为什么
还会是什么情况
What else would it be about?
其他人都以为蒙哥马利是为
Everyone here thinks Montgomery died
将警察杀手绳之于法而殉职
bringing a cop killer to justice.
只有我们知道他到底趟了什么浑水
We're the only ones who know what he was really involved in
还有他和你妈妈那件凶杀案的关联
and his connection to your mother's murder.
贝克特  这不可能是巧合
Beckett, it can't be a coincidence.
再查一下死者的前科
Recheck the vic's rap sheet.
看看蒙哥马利有没有逮捕过他
See if Montgomery was involved in any of his old arrests,
去查那个号码
and get on that number.
我要知道他死前和谁通过电话
I want to know who he was talking to just before he died.
跟我说点安慰的话
Say something reassuring.
纽约市每年都有上千件入室行窃的案子
There are thousands of break-ins in New York City every year.
这件感觉不同
This one feels different.
那也不表示它就真的不同了
Well, that doesn't mean that it is.
蒙哥马利查过数百件案子
Montgomery worked hundreds of cases.
单凭这人在找文件
Just because this guy was after files
也不能确定就是在找你妈妈那件案子的
doesn't mean he was after your mom's case.
那这个小偷怎么会死
Then why is our thief dead?
你也知道和蒙哥马利跟谁搅在了一起
You know those people that Montgomery was involved with,
他说他们要我死
he said that they wanted me dead,
我离真相太近了
that I was getting too close,
还说他要用他的生命
and he said that he was gonna give his life
来保护我
in order to protect mine,
而他们却仍要杀我
And they still tried to kill me.
我有时醒来  问我自己
I wake up sometimes, and I think to myself,
我怎么还活着
how the hell am I still alive?
我就像是在等着出事
It's like I'm just waiting for that other shoe to drop.
如果我等的就是这个呢
What if this is that other shoe?
她的情况总算开始好转
Things were finally getting better for her,
我们之间也是
for us.
她刚刚开始敞开心扉
She was just coming out of her shell,
却又出这种事
and now this?
你真觉得这跟她母亲的谋杀案有关吗
Do you really think it's related to her mother's murder case?
希望没有
I hope to god it isn't.
蒙哥马利的朋友说得很清楚
Montgomery's friend was very clear.
她要是去查她妈妈的案子
She starts poking around her mother's murder,
他们会再次找上她
they'll come after her again.
我不能让这事发生
I can't let that happen.
我知道
I know.
谢谢
Thank you.
你睡觉了吗
Did you get any sleep?
没怎么睡
Not much.
死者调查有没有进展
Anything new on our victim?
我们重新查了奥兰多的前科
We rechecked Orlando's rap sheet.
蒙哥马利没有涉及任何他以前的案子
Montgomery wasn't involved in any of his old arrests.
入室行窃并非出于个人恩怨
That break-in wasn't personal.
他被害前打的那个电话呢
What about the call he made before he was killed?
对方用的是一次性手机  没有登记机主
It's from a burner phone. There's no registered owner.
你不是一个人
You're not in this alone.
有我呢
I'm here.
我知道
I know.
我们对入室行窃的动机可能猜错了
We may have been wrong about why they hit Montgomery's.
几个证人称看到一名西班牙裔男子
Witnesses saw a Hispanic male fleeing the alley
开一辆褐色的帝威逃离巷子
in a late-model maroon Deville.
他脖子上有个帮派刺青
Apparently he had gang ink on his neck--
一头由字母C框着的狮子
a lion framed by a "C."
卡扎多斯帮
Cazador?
也就是死者以前混过的帮派
The very same gang that our victim ran with.
帮派
Gangs.
如果这家伙确实去过巷子
If this guy was in that alley,
有可能是他杀了奥兰多
odds are, he killed Orlando.
有人看到车牌没
Did we get a license plate?
没有  不过帮派专案组称
Uh, no, but according to gang task force,
一个叫文森特·德加多的人就开这车
the ride matches the car of one Vicente Delgado.
此人是卡扎多斯帮的头头
High-level shot caller for the Cazadores.
听这个
And get this.
他表兄蒂亚戈·古铁雷斯
His cousin Diego Gutierrez
在九五年因一起双尸案被蒙哥马利逮捕
was busted by Montgomery for a double homicide in '95.
蒙哥马利死后一个月
His lawyer's filed a motion for retrial
其律师就提出了重审的上诉
a month after Montgomery was killed.
把他找来
Find him.
纽约警局  双手都举起来
NYPD! Let me see your hands right now!
不许动  不许动
Don't move! Don't move! Don't move!
把手举起来
Let me see your hands!
看呐
Well, look here,
九毫米口径
a 9 millimeter.
跟杀害奥兰多·科斯塔斯的枪一样
Just like the gun that killed Orlando Costas.
都说了  我根本没去过巷子
I already told you, I was nowhere near that alley.
你的目击证人肯定瞎了狗眼
Fact is, your witnesses are blind.
你认识奥兰多·科斯塔斯
The fact is, you knew Orlando Costas.
以前认识  后来他离帮了
Yeah, I knew him once, before he turned his back.
他最近一次联系你是什么时候
When was the last time you heard from him.
-多年前了  -几小时才对
- Not in years. - Hours.
他死前往一个一次性手机上打过电话
Just before he was killed, Orlando called a burner cell,
而这手机在你身上
same phone that we found on you.
老实交代吧  省去三十年的牢狱之灾
So why don't you just admit to it and save yourself 30 years?
是你让他闯入罗伊·蒙哥马利家
You had him break in to Roy Montgomery's house
把你表兄案子的文件偷出来
and steal your cousin's case files,
然后干掉了他
and then you shot him.
你有什么证据  小妞
What you got, chica, huh?
我的枪肯定对不上
Gun's not gonna be a match.
你也就只有一通电话
So that leaves you with what, a phone call,
几个声称看到一辆普通车子的证人
and a couple of people who saw a very common car?
知道你为什么没法给我定罪吗  小妞
You know why you can't pin this on me, chica?
我根本没去现场
I wasn't there.
不在个鬼
The hell you weren't.
这是弹道报告出来了
That's gonna be ballistics.
想做交易这是最后的机会
Last chance to make a deal.
准备起诉他私藏毒品和枪支
Book him on the drugs and weapons charge
告诉区检我要提出一级谋杀的罪名
and tell the D.A. I'm gonna want to file for murder one.
不是他干的
It wasn't him.
什么叫不是他干的
What do you mean, it wasn't him?
蕾妮从死者指甲里
The skin tissue that Lanie was able to scrape
刮出了一些皮肤组织
from underneath our victim's fingernails,
实验室做了DNA检验
the lab was able to pull DNA.
我们拿它跟文森特的比过了
We ran it against Vicente.
结果不符
It's not a match.
而且在整个系统都找不到匹配
In fact, it wasn't a match to anyone in the system.
不过它跟另一个犯罪现场发现的DNA相符
But it did match DNA trace evidence found at another crime scene.
至少还有线索  哪个犯罪现场
Well, at least that's something. What was the crime scene?
一起枪击案
It was a shooting.
贝克特  是你那起枪击案
Beckett, it was your shooting.
DNA检验结果确定
DNA confirms that the man
杀害奥兰多·科斯塔斯的凶手
who killed Orlando Costas in that alley
跟向你开枪的枪手是同一个人
is the same man who put a bullet in your heart.
11个月都没有线索  现在却出了这事
No leads for 11 months, and now this.
告诉盖茨了吗
Does Gates know?
还没
No.
那就不告诉她
Then we don't tell her.
如果她知道这跟我那个案子有关
If she finds out this is a match to my shooting,
她会把我踢出这个案子
she'll take me off the case.
或许你是不该插手此案
Maybe you should be off this case.
他们试图杀你  凯特
They tried to kill you once, Kate.
你继续追查  他们...
You keep going on this, they...
他们怎么会不再下杀手
What's to stop them from trying again?
他们现在为何不下杀手
What's to stop them now?
不行
No.
我已经为此等了一年了
I've been waiting a year for this,
我绝不会让别人把这事搞砸了
and I'll be damned if I let someone else screw it up.
哈维尔
Hey, Javier.
伙计  这样不好吧
Man, this just feels wrong.
我们得告诉盖茨
We need to tell Gates.
告诉她干嘛
Why...
让她把贝克特赶回家吗
So she can send Beckett home?
你认为这能行吗
You think that's gonna work?
你认为这能阻止她吗
You think that's gonna stop her?
凯文  不论如何
She's gonna investigate this case, Kevin,
她都会调查这个案子的
whether she's on it or not.
至少
The least we can do
要确保有我们罩着她
is make sure that we have her back.
你好
Hello.
你知道我找你什么事吧  卡塞尔先生
I think you know why I'm calling, Mr. Castle.
是你
It's you.
谢天谢地  到底怎么回事
Thank god. What the hell is going on?
为什么他们要闯进蒙哥马利家
Why'd they break in to Montgomery's place?
最可能的就是去善后
Well, most likely, it's a clean-up job.
确保蒙哥马利的文件里
Making sure that Montgomery had nothing else
没有能定罪的东西
incriminating in his files.
只要贝克特放弃调查
As long as Beckett drops her investigation,
王牌还都在我们手里
we still hold all the cards.
不行  她已经去找那个狙击手了
No, she's already on to her shooter.
她不会放手的
She's not gonna let go.
那就有麻烦了
Then we have a problem.
如果她不停止  他们就会报复
If she doesn't stop, they will retaliate.
如果你控制不了她
Now I can't control the situation
我也控制不了局面
if you can't control her.
光是毒品和枪支的指控
I got enough on the drug and weapons charges
就足够让你坐五年牢了
to put you away for at least five years.
生命中的五年...
Five years of your life...
那有什么价值
What's that worth?
我知道你没杀奥兰多
I know you didn't kill Orlando.
但他给你打了电话
But he called you,
你和他谈了两分钟
and you talked to him for two minutes,
而且你去过那个巷子
and you were in that alley.
为什么
Why?
这里除了你和我没有其他人
There's nobody in here but you and me.
这里没有摄像头
There's no cameras,
没有麦克风  没人在听
no microphones, no one's listening.
我能撤销所有指控
I can make all those charges go away.
还你五年的生命
Five years of your life back,
但是你得告诉我你知道什么
but you gotta tell me what you know.
他上周打电话给我
He called last week.
说"时运不济啊"
Talking about "Times were bad,"
所以我告诉他"我能给你份工作"
So I told him, "I can get you some work."
但是他知道  如果他回到卡扎多斯帮
But he knew if he came back to the Cazadores,
这次就出不去了
there'd be no leaving this time.
他就是想借点钱
And all he really wanted was a loan
求我看在以前的份上帮他一把
and could I help him out for old times' sake.
你借他了吗
Did you give it to him?
没有  他求我了
No. He begged me.
他说他能还上
Said he was good for it.
说他有笔大买卖
Said he had something big coming up,
让他有钱可周转
something that'd make him whole.
他说是什么了吗
Did he say what?
没有  但那天早晨  我电话响了
No, but that morning, my phone rings,
他说事情出了岔子
and he said it'd all gone wrong,
他很绝望  说他们要杀了他
he was desperate, talking about they were gonna kill him.
他们是谁
Who's they?
不知道
Don't know.
但他害怕极了
But he was scared.
他为什么给你打电话
Why did he call you?
寻求保护  小妞
Protection, Chica.
他说如果我帮他  他会回到帮里
He said if I helped him out, he'd come back,
他知道那就是代价
and he knew that was the price.
于是我告诉他在哪见
So I told him where to meet.
但我到的时候  他已经死了
But by the time I got there, he was already dead.
你定的地点
You told him where to meet?
没错
That's right.
-没告诉别人吧  -没有
- You didn't tell anyone else? - No.
你在那儿看见什么了吗
Did you see anything there?
一个白人  1米8
White guy, 6'.
跑进夜色之前我瞄到了一眼
Caught a glimpse before the night swallowed him whole.
他们一定窃听了奥兰多的电话
They must have been tapping Orlando's phone.
只有这样他们才能先到那里
That's the only way they got there first.
但他们为什么找上奥兰多呢
But how did they know to target Orlando for the job?
因为他非常想要钱
Because he was desperate for money.
对  但他们怎么知道的呢
Yeah, but how did they know that?
他们怎么知道他的背景的
How did they know his background?
是军队里认识的人
Because they knew him from the military.
他是被熟人雇佣的
He was hired by somebody he knew.
可以从这里开始查起
It's a place to start.
但是接近那个秘密的人都死了
But whoever's gotten close to that secret is dead.
情况很清楚  这事我们管不了
I think it's clear, we're in over our heads here.
那是你自己的看法  兄弟
Speak for yourself, bro.
奥兰多的财务状况出来了
Orlando's financials just came in.
直到上周  他一直负债  透支
He was underwater and overdrawn until last week
直到他账户上收到了一万美金的电子汇款
when a wire transfer for 10 grand hit his account.
怕是追踪不到来源吧
Let me guess. Untraceable?
那就没办法了
So it's a dead end.
存款查不了
The deposits are,
但可追查借记卡取款记录
but the debit withdrawals are not.
钱刚打进去
Right when the money came in,
玛丽萨尔就在用卡付款了
Marisol started using it to pay bills.
等一下  如果玛丽萨尔知道钱的事
Wait. If Marisol knew about the money...
那她一定清楚奥兰多没干好事
Then she knew Orlando was up to something.
她骗了我们
She lied to us.
不仅如此  银行方面称
Not only that, but according to the bank,
一小时前她提走了账户的全部资金
she cleaned out the entire account an hour ago.
她准备跑路了
She's on the run.
在你离开之前  我有几个问题想问你
I've got a few questions for you before you leave town,
而这一次
and this time,
我要听真相
I want the truth.
我说的是事实
I'm telling you the truth.
我此前不了解钱的事情
I didn't know anything about the money.
今天才知道的
Not until today.
那为何钱刚一到账
So why do we have debits against it
你就立马把钱提走
the moment it appeared in your account?
-是奥兰多  -那是你的卡  玛丽萨尔
- Orlando-- - It was your card, Marisol.
奥兰多在为谁效力
Who was Orlando working for?
你知道不与我们合作的下场是什么吗
Do you know what's gonna happen if you don't cooperate?
你会蹲进大牢
You're gonna go to jail
而你的孩子会被送去寄养家庭
and your kid's gonna go to foster care.
-那是你想要的吗  -贝克特
- Is that what you want? - Beckett--
到时马克就会游荡大街  像他爸一样
Marco on the streets, enlisted by the cazadores
十岁就被拉去当混混
at age 10 like his father,
十九岁就死于非命
dead in a gutter at 19!
你去死
Pudrete en el infierno!
贝克特  够了
Beckett... That's enough.
奥兰多说那是他在部队里认识的一个人
Orlando said it was someone he knew from the service,
是个危险人物
someone dangerous.
但活儿是一次性的
But it was just a one-off,
轻而易举就能拿不少钱
a lot of money for an easy job.
而我们非常拮据
And we needed the money.
究竟是什么工作
What was the job?
他们需要一个
They needed files...
已故警察家里的文件
from a dead cop's house.
什么文件
What files?
所有文件  只要能找到的
All of them, any he could find.
那你知道部队里那人的名字吗
This guy from the service, did you get a name?
-不知道  -你见过他没
- No. - Did you meet him?
没有
No.
他往家里打过电话吗
Did he ever call the house?
他在邮箱里留了纸条
He left notes for Orlando in the mail box
说明时间地点
with a time and place.
是用密码写的  所以我看不懂
They were coded so I-I wouldn't know where.
但我有次在车里
But I was in the car once.
看到他们的见面地点了
I saw where they met.
是个教堂
At a church
在道富银行旁边
over on State Street.
你说周三是吗
Wednesday, you say?
对  下午三点左右
Yeah, around 3:00 p.m.
他在与某人会面
He was meeting with someone.
抱歉  我也希望能帮上忙
I'm sorry. I wish I could help.
但我们教堂是对外公开的
But we're open to the public,
每天都有许多混杂人员出入
and we get a lot of unfamiliar faces every day.
我们通常让他们自己祷告
We usually just leave them to their prayers.
从你的捐赠箱来看
If your donation box is any indication,
对外公开也是要付出代价的啊
it looks like being open to the public comes with a price.
是啊  这一片比较混乱
Yes, well... it's not the best neighborhood.
我们经常能抓到小混混或者流浪者
We catch gang kids and the homeless all the time,
想从我们这里捞点好处
trying to take advantage of more than just our outreach programs.
怎么抓呢
How do you catch them?
就这里  周三下午三点
Here it is, 3 p.m. Wednesday.
是奥兰多
There's Orlando.
他出现了
That's him.
该死
Damn it.
快出来
Come on.
有了
Yes.
原来你长这个样子
So that's what you look like.
我把图像拿去用军队信息系统查一下
I'm gonna run this through army C.I.D.
如果他们在部队相识  那奥兰多
If they met in the military someone in Orlando's old unit
以前部队的战友或许能认出他
might be able to I.D. Him.
不行  我们不知此事涉及何人
No, no, we don't know who's involved
也不知事态会上升到何种等级
and we don't know how high this goes.
我们把相片公开
The minute we put this photo out there,
就如同打草惊蛇  他到时趁机逃跑
these people are gonna know. He's gonna disappear,
我们就再也找不到他了
and we'll never see him again.
这次我们得自己查
We have to do this one on our own.
贝克特  那是不可能的
Beckett, that's impossible.
我们只有一张相片
All we have is a face--
不清楚姓名  身份  无从下手啊
no name, no I.D., no way to find this guy.
那我们就要找个方法来找到他
Then we will find a way to find him.
我不会放弃这条线索的
I'm not gonna lose this lead.
我们不能动手查的话
How are we supposed to investigate
那要怎么查呢
if we can't investigate?
你听到她说的了
You heard the lady.
我们要另寻他法
We find a way.
你把恶魔唤醒了
You woke the dragon.
这事比你想象中要严重得多
And this is so much bigger than you realize.
凯特
Kate!
撑住
Don't die!
逃不出我的手掌
He can't hide from me.
你弄反了
You got it ass backwards.
是你逃不出他的手掌
You can't hide from him.
我犯了一个大错
I made a bad mistake.
是谁雇得你
Who hired you to kill her?
别管了  你永远都撼动不了他们
Forget it. You'll never touch 'em.
我刚跟埃斯波西托通完电话
I just got off the phone with Esposito.
凶手手上有个钥匙串
Our killer had a keychain,
和屹威汽车租赁公司的相吻合
and he matched it to Eastway Car Rentals.
那可能是一千辆车里的某一个
That could be any one of a thousand cars.
我知道  就像大海捞针一样
I know, it's a needle in a haystack,
但起码我们找到了那片海
but at least it's a haystack,
而且很多档案都在
And they keep most of their licenses on file.
-凯特  -是  他很可能用的是假身份证
- Kate-- - Yeah, he's probably using a fake I.D.
但是我们应该能从那儿缩小范围
But we should be able to narrow it down from there.
-凯特  -怎么了
- Kate. - What's wrong?
你...
You, um...
你得停手了
You have to stop.
这个调查你不能再继续下去了
This investigation, you--you have to stop.
卡塞尔  这件事我们已经讨论过了
Castle, we already talked about this.
我没事  我控制得住
I'm fine. I'm in control.
不  你控制不了
No, you're not.
他们才是掌控者
They are.
如果你还不停手  他们会杀了你  凯特
And if you don't stop, they will kill you, Kate.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
蒙哥马利进机库之前
Before Montgomery went into that hangar,
寄了一个包裹给一个人
he sent a package to someone,
一个他信任的人
someone... he trusted.
里面的信息
It contained information
可以毁掉这一切事件的幕后黑手
damaging to the person behind all this.
蒙哥马利想保护你
Montgomery was trying to protect you.
但是你被枪击之后  包裹才寄到
but the package didn't arrive until after you'd been shot.
蒙哥马利的朋友
Montgomery's friend...
跟他们达成了协议
struck a deal with them.
如果他们不再找你麻烦
If they left you alone,
包裹里的信息
that package and the information inside
永远都不会曝光
would never see the light of day.
但他们提了一个要求  你必须放弃调查
But they made one condition-- you had to back off.
所以你还活着  凯特
And that's the reason you're alive, Kate,
因为你罢手了
because you stopped.
你怎么知道的
How do you know this?
为了确保交易生效
In order for the deal to work,
要有人能保证你不再追究这件案子
someone had to make sure you weren't pursuing it.
这个人是你吗
Are you a part of this?
我只是想保护你
I was just trying to keep you safe.
通过对我撒谎吗
By lying to me
对我生命中最重要的事撒谎吗
about the most important thing in my life?
只有说谎才能保护你
That lie was the only thing that was protecting you.
卡塞尔  我不需要保护
Castle, I didn't need protection.
我要的是线索
I needed a lead,
你却瞒了我一年
and you sat on it for a year.
这个人是谁  我怎么才能找到他
Now who is this person? How do I find him?
我只听过他的声音
He's a-a voice on the phone.
在停车场里看过一个阴影
He's a shadow in a parking garage.
你见过他
You met with him?
你怎么能知道他不是幕后黑手
How do you know that he's not behind my mom's murder?
你怎么知道他没卷进那个案子
How do you know that he's not involved?
你怎么能这么做
And how the hell could you do this?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
不过你已经知道了  对吗
But you already know that, don't you?
你已经知道一年了
You've known for about a year.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
你现在来追究这个
You're actually bringing this up right now,
在你说了背叛我之后吗
after you told me that you just betrayed me?
凯特  听我说
Kate, listen to me--
听你说  我为什么要听你的
Listen to you? Why should I listen to you?
我怎么能再相信你的任何一句话
How I am even supposed to trust anything that you say?
你怎么...
How are you s--
就凭我们这些年一起经历过的事
Because of everything we've been through together!
四年了  我一直在你身边
Four years, I've been right here.
四年来  我一直在等你能睁眼看看
Four years just waiting for you to just open your eyes,
看看我在你身边
to see that I'm right here
不仅仅只是个搭档
and that I'm more than a partner.
每天早上  我带咖啡给你
Every morning, I-I bring you a cup of coffee
就是想看到你脸上的微笑
just so I could see a smile on your face
因为我觉得你是我见过的...
because I think you are the most...
最出色
remarkable...
最令人疯狂
maddening...
最富挑战性
challenging...
最让人挫败的人
frustrating person I have ever met.
我爱你  凯特  如果...
And I love you, Kate, and if...
这件事对你还有一丁点意义
that means anything to you,
如果你还在乎我  哪怕一点点
If you care about me at all,
别再纠结这件事了
just don't do this.
如果我在乎你
If I care about you?
卡塞尔  你为了我的性命做交易
Castle, you cut a deal for my life
就跟我是小孩子一样
like I was some kind of a child.
这是我的命  我的
My life, mine...
你没权利做决定
you don't get to decide.
如果你还不放手
You keep going with this,
决定权就在他们手上了
they're gonna decide.
他们就会来对付你  凯特
They're gonna come for you, Kate.
让他们放马过来
Let them come.
库南来了  死了
They sent Coonan, and he is dead.
洛克伍德来了  也死了
They sent Lockwood, and he is dead.
我还活得好好的  卡塞尔
And I am still here, Castle,
我准备好了
and I am ready.
准备好什么
Ready for what,
为了你的事业献身吗
To-to die for your cause?
这已不再是单纯的凶案调查了  凯特
This isn't a murder investigation anymore, Kate.
他们已经将此升级成战争了
They've turned it into a war.
如果他们想要战争  我乐意奉陪
If they want a war, then I will bring them a war,
打到他们老巢去
straight to their doorsteps.
我没法说服你了  是吗
Well, I guess there's just nothing I can say, is there?
好吧
Okay, um...
你是对的  凯特
Yeah, you're right, Kate,
这是你自己的生命
It's your life.
你有权利舍弃它
You can throw it away if you want,
但我绝不会眼睁睁看着
but I'm not gonna stick around and watch you,
所以这一切
So this is, uh...
结束了
over.
我退出
I'm done.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
-好  -你演讲准备得怎样了
- Yeah. Fine. - How's your speech coming?
我已经把所有毕业演讲
I have watched or read
都观看或是阅读过了
every graduation address ever written
并且把其中所有好建议都汇编到一个演讲中
and compiled all the best advice into one speech,
然后我再大声朗读出来
and then I read it out loud.
你知道我听起来像什么
And guess what I sounded like.
像个自大狂
Like a pompous ass.
我只有18岁  又能懂什么大道理呢
I'm 18 years old. What the hell do I know?
听我说  你所懂得的一切
Hey, look, everything you know,
和你所将要懂得的一切
everything you will know is...
对你来说都是真实的
is what's true for you.
我只知道  一切都在改变
All I know is, everything's changing.
一切都会时过境迁
Everything's going to be different,
我很害怕
and I'm so scared.
害怕什么
Of what?
朝前看
Moving on.
把这个写下来
Write about that.
这种感觉很真切
That feels true.
乔安娜·贝克特
真理征服一切
卡塞尔呢
Where's Castle?
他退出了
He's off the team.
我们有什么进展吗
So what do we got?
屹威汽车租赁公司上周三共出租了700辆车
Eastway rented 700 cars last wednesday.
我们认为嫌疑人使用化名
We believe our suspect is going under the name
科尔·马多克斯来登记
Cole Maddox.
他从肯尼迪机场将车租出
He rented out of J.F.K.
使用了堪萨斯的驾驶执照
It's a kansas driver's license.
经过调查我们发现这是伪造的身份
Now we did some digging. It's a cover I.D.
他把车归还了吗
Did he return the car?
没有  但是
No, but...
屹威对其所有车辆
Eastway maintains
都实施了GPS跟踪
GPS tracking on all of its equipment,
所以我们追踪到了下东区
So we tracked it to the lower east side
锁定在这个方圆一街区的地方
to a 1-block radius somewhere along here.
你继续保持监视
All right, you stay on grid.
如果他离开就通知我们
Let us know if he moves.
埃斯波西托  你和我行动
Esposito, you're coming with me.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
如果你真要去抓他  就该布置周密
You want to do this, you do it right.
派一支小队控制住车子  并且带上后援
You put a team on that car and you bring backup with you.
莱恩  这一切都源起于
Ryan, this whole thing started
一群堕落的警察
because of a group of corrupt cops.
你怎么能轻易相信他人
How do you know there aren't more out there?
我们就要抓到他了
We're about an inch away from catching this guy,
我可不想大肆声张  功亏一篑
and I'm not gonna blow it by advertising our next move.
恕我直言
With all due respect,
这家伙朝你心脏开了一枪后
this guy put a bullet in your heart
就销声匿迹了
and then he disappeared into the ether.
你不能打无准备的仗啊
You cannot go in there unprepared.
无准备
Unprepared?
我13年来一直在准备着这一刻
I've been preparing for this for the past 13 years.
哈维尔
Hey, Javier...
兄弟  别让她这么做
Man, don't let her do this.
太冒险了
It's too big of a risk.
没问题的  老兄
It's all good, bro.
我们能行的
We got this.
快点  我们可不能错过她的演讲
Come on. We don't want to miss her speech...
甚至整个毕业典礼
or the entire graduation.
我差不多准备好了
I'm almost ready.
我们发现他的踪迹了
Hey, we got him.
街对面住宿旅店的保安
The doorman at the residency hotel across the way
认出了那辆车
I.D.'ed the car.
前台职员证实了
And the front desk clerk confirms
马多克斯先生在这儿租了一个月的房子
that Mr. Maddox is here on a 1-month lease.
他们已经同意我们进屋查看了
They've agreed to let us in his room.
让开一下
Get out of the way.
安全
Clear.
蒙哥马利的文件
Montgomery's files.
他的联系人列表
His contact list?
他们到底在找什么东西
What the hell were they looking for?
不是找东西  是找人
Not what. Who.
他们偷来了蒙哥马利的婚礼相册
They grabbed Montgomery's wedding album.
-为什么  -他们在寻找他的某个熟人
- Why? - They're looking for someone that he knew.
说不定已经找到了
Maybe they found him.
我们赶快出去
We gotta get out of here.
我去叫后援
I'm gonna call for backup.
我们在酒店大堂...
We'll set up in the lobby--
告诉我幕后主谋是谁
Just tell me who's behind this.
你在浪费时间  探长
You're wasting your time, detective.
你对自己面临的一切全然不知
You have no idea what you're up against.
你也一样
Neither do you.
事实上
Actually...
我们心知肚明
We know exactly who we're up against.
救命
Help!
上帝啊
Oh! Oh, god.
别
No!
别这样对我  加把劲
Oh, not like this. Come on.
加把劲  不
Come on. No!
卡塞尔
Castle.
贝克特
Beckett!
卡塞尔
Castle!
-贝克特  -卡塞尔  我在这
- Beckett! - Castle, I'm here!
不
No!
天啊  卡塞尔
Oh, god. Castle!
贝克特  坚持住
Beckett, hang on!
卡塞尔
Castle!
贝克特
Beckett!
卡塞尔
Castle?
隐瞒证据
With holding evidence,
对上级撒谎
lying to a superior officer--
你们的行为令纽约蒙羞  令警局蒙羞
What you did dishonors this city and dishonors the badge.
你们都被调离此案
Not only are you off this investigation,
我现在就让你们
I'm putting you both on administrative leave
-停职  -长官
- effective immediately. - Sir--
别叫我长官
Don't you "Sir" me.
你们不配当警察
You don't deserve to wear the uniform.
交出你们的警徽和配枪
Now hand over your badges and guns.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
收好了
Keep it.
我辞职
I resign.
有一普遍真理
There's a universal truth
我们无法逃避
we all have to face...
不论我们是否情愿
Whether we want to or not,
万物皆有终结的一天
everything eventually ends.
我期盼这天到来的同时
As much as I've looked forward to this day,
却也有着不舍与留恋
I've always disliked endings...
好比夏日的最后一天
The last day of summer...
好书的最后一章
The final chapter of a great book...
与密友离别
Parting ways with a close friend.
结局从来不可避免
But endings are inevitable.
哈维
Javi.
我做了我必须做的
I had to.
秋叶飘落
Leaves fall.
你合上手中的书
You close the book.
与朋友话别
You say good-bye.
于我们而言  这是美好的一天
Today is one of those days for us.
今天  我们与过去告别
Today we say good-bye to everything that was familiar,
告别那些曾经的熟悉与安逸
everything that was comfortable.
我们继续前进
We're moving on.
但终因离别
But just because we're leaving,
而心痛万分
and that hurts...
那些已然走进
There are some people
我们生活的人
who are so much a part of us
无论何时  都将与我们同在
they'll be with us no matter what.
他们是我们坚强的后盾
They are our solid ground...
我们的北极星
our north star,
心底那声清吟
and the small clear voices in our hearts
将永远在我们的耳畔萦绕
that will be with us... always.
阿丽克西斯  别担心我
No, Alexis, I'll be fine.
这么多电视节目  还有游戏机呢
I got a thousand cable channels, I got my xbox.
玩得开心点
You have fun.
明天午饭前我是不会担心你的
I will not worry about you until lunchtime tomorrow.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
贝克特  你想怎样
Beckett, what do you want?
我想要你
You.
卡塞尔  我很抱歉
I'm so sorry, Castle.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
发生什么事了
What happened?
他跑了  可我不在乎
He got away, and I didn't care.
在频临死亡的那一刻
I almost died
我心里想的只有你
and all I could think about was you.
我只想跟你在一起
I just want you.
史密斯
Mister...
先生
Smith?
你是谁
Who are you?
你真不好找啊
You've been a very hard man to find.
你想干什么
What do you want?
你手中握有对我雇主不利的东西
You have some sensitive information about my employer,
就是你用来保护
information that you've been using
贝克特的信息
to protect Detective Beckett.
你难道忘了
Are you forgetting...
我们之间的协议吗
we have a deal?
那不是协议  是勒索
No. What you had was blackmail.
现在你得告诉我东西在哪
Now you're gonna tell me where all that information is,
在那之后
and after you do,
我要送凯特·贝克特归西
I'm gonna put Kate Beckett in the ground once and for all.